Lloyd: So now that you've completed
session three of unit five, it's
time to complete the relevant
section of the assessment booklet.
So if you open your assessment
booklet and scroll down to section
three, you can see that this is
Understand the Use of Firewalls.
So there's four learning objectives, and
there are four questions to allow you
to fulfill those learning objectives.
So question one is quite straightforward.
It's asking you to define
the term firewall, so what is
the definition of a firewall?
Again, try and put it in your own
words rather than just copying
the definition from the course
materials or an external site.
And then for question two,
it's asked you to describe the
key functions of a firewall.
So what is the purpose of a firewall?
What does it do?
I would suggest for this one is to
look back at the course materials and
think about the different types of
firewalls and how they are applied.
Do you have a firewall on your computer?
What is the purpose?
Have you done anything with it?
Did you install a firewall or is it
just already a part of your system?
So again, what is the
function of the firewall?
And you can personalise the
answer by explaining what the
firewall does for your PC.
For question three, it's asking you define
what is meant by network traffic, so what
is the definition of network traffic?
What is the straightforward definition
of network traffic that's going across
a network from computer to computer?
And for question four, it's asked you to
explain the advantages and disadvantage of
using a firewall to protect from threats.
So think about the various
advantages and disadvantages.
A lot of them are mentioned on the
course materials, but you may also
have experience of advantages and
disadvantages from your own experience
of using a firewall, whether it
be at work or whether it be on
your home PC or your home network.
So again, explain the
advantages and disadvantage.
So you must give two advantages
and two disadvantages.
So once you've done that, I would
recommend reading through all of the
unit five assessment again, carrying
out a spelling and grammar check,
proofreading your work, make sure
that you're happy with your answers.
I would always suggest you adding
more detail if you feel that the
question or the response to a
question may be quite brief, try and
put as much detail in as possible.
And then once you've done that, you can
then save your unit five assessment and
send it off to your tutor for marking.